世界知名侦探小说家
What's so special about
里奇·卡塞尔究竟有何特别
World- famous mystery novelist Richard Castle?
他既多金  又英俊
He's rich, he's handsome
还把你作为下部最畅销小说的原型
And he's basing his next best seller on you.
告诉我  贝克特探长
Tell me, detective Beckett,
身为惊险故事大师理查德·卡塞尔笔下
What's it like being the inspiration for
新人物妮基·希特的原型  你有什么感受
Thrill master Richard Castle's New character Nikki Heat?
代表纽约警局  我们很荣幸
On behalf of the NYPD, it has been a pleasure
为卡塞尔先生了解警察这个职业  提供便捷
To offer Mr. Castle insight into the profession.
鉴于他的作品都是最畅销小说  很明显
Given all his best sellers, it's obvious Mr. Castle
卡塞尔先生对于犯罪心理有深刻认识
Has tremendous insight in the criminal mind.
常常有人告诉我  他参与侦查
I'm told in many occasions, his participation
帮助警方解决了不少难查的案子
Was essential to solving your toughest cases.
是吗
Really?
有人告诉你  谁告诉你的
You were told that? By who?
是卡塞尔
By Castle.
试着解开他的衬衫扣子  就第一颗
Try unbuttoning his shirt. Just, just the first one.
抱歉  我能离开会儿吗
Could you excuse me for a moment?
先生  我们私下谈谈行吗
Sir, could I talk to you in private
就一小会儿
For a moment, please?
-贝克特  我有很多事  -现在就谈
- Beckett, I have a couple-- Now.
贝克特  我们说好的
We had a deal, Beckett.
就到此为止
The deal is off.
怎么了
What's the problem?
不仅仅是因为
Not only does he have
外面那两个单身派对的警察姐妹花
The bachelor-party cop twins out there
把他当成钢管
Using him as a stripper pole,
而且  当我在帮他对媒体说好话的时候
While I make nicey-nice with the press,
-你可知道他说什么了  -什么
- But do you know what he said? - No.
他说他在案件侦查中
He said that he has been instrumental
帮了我们大忙
In helping us solve crimes.
他没有吗
Well, hasn't he?
那个不是重点
That's not the point.
你知道让媒体说纽约警局好话得多难吗
Do you know how hard it is for NYPD to get good press?
尤其是人们真的会去读的杂志
I mean, in a magazine that people actually read.
这篇文章对市长很重要
This article is very important to the mayor.
因此我们的工作就是  合作
Therefore, we are going to cooperate.
听懂我的意思了吗
Do I make myself clear?
好  算了
Okay. Fine.
很高兴见到你
It was nice to meet you.
拍照的事可以多弄些
We should have photo shoots here more often.
贝克特  你怎么不穿那样的制服呢
Hey, Beckett, how come you don't wear a uniform like that?
因为我不想在酒吧领薪水
Because I don't want to get paid in singles.
我们不是还有件案子
Don't we have that thing?
没有
No.
就是那个家伙的案子
Yeah, you know, that thing with the guy?
对啊  那个家伙的案子
The thing with the guy.
你们慢慢谈
Yeah, excuse us.
我只想告诉你  这事和我一点关系也没有
I just wanted you to know, I had nothing to do with this.
这都是杂志社的主意
I mean, it was the magazine.
另外  市长认为这家媒体不错
And, and, well, the mayor thought it would be good press.
没必要解释这些
You don't have to explain yourself.
-真的  -真的  我已经无所谓了
- Really? - Really. See? I don't care anymore.
我现在能走开一会儿吗
Now if you'll excuse me,
我还有个采访得继续
I have an interview to get back to.
我倒底犯了什么大错
What did I do that was so wrong?
有件事我让你别去碰
The one thing I asked you not to do.
是的  你让我别查你母亲的案子
Okay. So you asked me not to look into your mother's murder,
但你听听我查到什么了
But look at what I found.
你查到什么都不重要
It doesn't matter what you found.
很久以前  我就都放下了
I put that all behind me a long time ago.
我们可以继续采访了
We can get back to the interview now.
不行  得重新约时间了  发现一具尸体
No, gonna have to reschedule. We just caught a body.
抱歉艾米  咱们得分道扬镳了
So sorry to step out on you, Amy.
别说笑了  这太完美了
Ooh, are you kidding? It's perfect.
直击卡塞尔办案的机会
A chance to see Castle in action.
我们的读者会非常喜欢的
Our readers will love it.
我们绝不会让读者失望的
Well, we wouldn't want to disappoint your readers,
是不是  探长
Now would we, detective?
能再谈谈吗
Hey. Can we talk about this, please?
我和你没什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
那至少让我知道
Well, just at least let me know
怎么做才能弥补我的过失
What I can do to make it up to you.
那拜托你走开
You could leave me alone.
我也试过
Yes. Well, I tried that,
不过也不管用
And it didn't work.
对了  我买匹小马驹送你怎么样
Hey, I could buy you a pony.
集中精神  卡塞尔
Focus, Castle.
这是犯罪现场  好吗
Crime scene, okay?
天上下着男人雨[气象女孩的一首歌]
It's raining men.
卡塞尔  你怎么来了
Castle, what are you doing here?
别担心  战争还没过去
Don't worry. We're still mad at him.
树上有个男孩  老爸老妈在争吵
Guy in a tree, mom and dad bickering--
看着和以前一样
Seems like old times.
在空中感觉如何
How's it going up there?
树枝戳到我的胸部
I got tree branches poking my boobs
闪关灯对准我的臀部
And spotlights shining up my booty.
算还不错了
Could be worse.
你还没穿裙子呢
You could be wearing a skirt.
等我下来  非得揍扁你
When I come down, I'm-a smack you.
-期待那一刻的到来  -接住
- I'll be looking forward to that.- Here.
死者为白人男性  35到39岁
Vic's a white male, late 30s.
从折断的树枝判断
Judging from the cracked branches,
他应该是模仿超人
I'm guessing he did a superman off
从那栋楼的楼顶跳下
the top of that building.
死者名叫约翰·艾伦
Vic's name is John Allen.
身份证地址显示他住在上西区
I.D. has him on the upper west side.
名片显示他从事保险业
Business card has him in insurance.
他是自杀吗
Is it a suicide?
-不是  -不是
- It's not a suicide. - It's not a suicide.
为什么
How do you know?
这栋楼不够高
Um, the building is too short.
除非他想摔成残废  而不是想自杀
He'd want to kill himself, not cripple himself.
要寻死
Well, if you want to die,
会选择水泥地  不会往树上跳
you're gonna aim for concrete, not a tree.
从跌落的角度判断
Judging from angle of descent,
我判断死者应该是被扔下楼的
I'd say that guy was thrown off the building.
既然很明显这不是自杀
Since it clearly wasn't a suicide,
那他的死因是什么
how did he die?
脖子有被勒过的痕迹
There are signs of strangulation.
看来气管是断了
It looks like his windpipe was crushed.
有没有绑缚物的痕迹
Any ligature marks?
-看不出  -绑缚物指的是
- Nope.-"Ligature" refers to
能捆绑的东西  比如绳子或者皮带
Anything that ties or binds, like a rope or a belt.
没有绑缚物的痕迹  表示他是被用手掐死的
Lack of any marks suggests he was strangled by hand.
你懂的真多
Wow. You really know your stuff.
难怪警方喜欢带着你
No wonder they like having you around.
他确实是不可多得的人才
You know what? He's such an incredible resource,
在这里简直太浪费他的才干了
It seems like a shame to waste his talents here in the field.
你不介意跟随帕里什医生去停尸房吧
Would you mind going back to the morgue with dr. Parish
看看在死者身上还有什么线索
To see what else we can find out about the vic?
你不觉得我在案发现场帮助更大吗
Don't you think I 'd be of more use here at the crime scene?
不会  我们就敲敲门
Oh, no. We're just gonna knock on doors
看看能否查到什么
And see what else we can stir up.
只是无聊的警察工作
You know, boring police stuff.
好的  但关于小马的事我是认真的
Fine. But I was serious about the pony.
这边  我领你参观移动停尸房
Come on, I'll show you the, uh, morgue...mobile.
-钱包里有什么线索吗  -没有
- Anything in the wallet? - No.
只有干洗的票据  身份证和信用卡
Dry cleaning tickets, I.D., two credit cards.
但现金没有了
Cash was missing, though.
这可完全不是抢劫
That's a long way to go for a robbery.
难道我们要和尸体一起坐车
You mean we have to ride with the body?
你可以坐我在前排的座位
You can take my seat up front.
真的吗
You sure?
是的  我习惯了和尸体在一起
Mm-hmm. I'm used to hanging out with stiffs.
你不用跟我套近乎
Unh-unh. You do not get to say hi to me.
我只是帮我的朋友而已
I'm just doing my girl a favor.
你也这样吗
Oh, you, too, huh?
你以为呢
Well, what did you expect?
贝克特当警察的头三年里
Beckett spent the first three years of being a cop
都在努力查清她母亲的案子
Trying to solve her mother's murder.
她付出很多才能放下这事
It took everything that she had to put it behind her.
你不能尊重她的感受吗
You couldn't respect that?
那我该怎么办
What was I supposed to do,
隐瞒我的发现吗
Not tell her what I'd found?
你的发现
What you found?
她没告诉你  是吗
Oh, she didn't tell you, did she?
有三名死者和她母亲的遭遇一样
Three people were killed the same way her mother was
而且时间大致相同
Right about the same time.
其中一个是她以前的法律系学生
One of 'em was a former law student of hers.
还有一个是文员
Another one, a documents clerk.
第三个是非盈利组织的律师
The third one, a lawyer for a nonprofit.
等等  当时的法医
Wait, the M.E. at the time
没把这些线索联系起来吗
Didn't make the connection?
如果发现了  也隐瞒了
If he did, he buried it.
你和他谈过了吗
Did you talk to him?
他四年前死了
He died four years ago.
所以我必须告诉她这些
So you see why I had to tell her.
她说了什么
What did she say?
她说我们结束了
That we were done.
然后她走到
And then she just walked--
都不许动  不许动
Don't move! Don't move!
快拿尸体
Get the body!
走
Go!
不许动
Don't move!
快  快点
Come on, move! Come on!
是只有我觉得怪异
Is it just me,
还是这就是非常非常怪异
Or was that really, really weird.
灵书妙探  第二季
第一集
-他怎么样  -死不了
- Well? - He'll live.
没有脑损伤吗
What, no brain damage?
如果有  也是以前就造成的
If he has some, it happened way before tonight,
而且是他自己造成的
And it was probably self-inflicted.
那些美好的时光啊
Ahh. Good times.
路易斯·蓝恩[超人前传中女记者]怎么样
How's Lois Lane?
谁  那个女记者
Who, reporter chick?
我们给她录完口供  就送她回家了
We took her statement and we sent her home.
已经全面通缉那辆轿车
We got an A.P.B. On the sedan,
犯罪现场小组正在梳理屋顶的线索
C.S.U.S are combing the rooftop,
已经派军装警察
And we got unis looking for
去查看现场的监控录像了
surveillance footage of the crash site.
我实在搞不懂
You know what I don't get
什么人会偷尸体
Is who would steal a dead body?
可能有很多人
Oh, plenty of people--
非法贩卖器官的贩子
Uh, organ harvesters,
急缺尸体标本的医学院学生
Cadaverless med students,
撒旦崇拜者
Satanists,
想制造怪物的科学狂人
Mad scientists looking to create their own monster.
或者是杀他的凶手
Or the guys who killed him
在尸体上留下了证据
Might have left some evidence behind.
没创意
Boring.
这个想法怎样  一个间谍
How about a spy
吞下了有最高机密的微晶片
Having swallowed a top-secret microchip
于是敌人在中情局抓到他之前
That the enemy forces murder him over
把他杀掉了
Before the C.I.A. can get a hold of him?
尽管我们都很欣赏你的洞察力
As much as we all appreciate your insightful
和你有可能但难以置信的理论
And incredibly believable theories,
《时尚》的记者小姐已经走了
Miss "Cosmo" is gone,
我想你也能回家了
so I believe you can go home now.
回家吗  不行
Home? No. No, no, no.
这个案子刚有转机
This, this case just got good.
而且  我是目击证人
And, and I'm, I'm a witness.
我就让你再跟这一个案子
All right, I'll let you work this one case with me
但你要保证结案后  别再烦我
If you promise to leave me alone when it's over
而且别再耍诡计混回来
And not to weasel your way back in.
说定了
Deal.
但我也警告你  探长
But fair warning, detective.
我会让你改变主意的
I will make you change your mind.
我不会
I won't.
你会
You won't.
那下一步做什么  去死者家吗
so what's the next step, victim's family?
我猜把尸体带回去的  不是他家人
Huh. I didn't think she'd take him back.
-是艾伦女士吗  -是的
- Mrs. Allen? - Yes.
这事有关你的丈夫
It's about your husband.
他本来还在家的
He was just right here
不过就几个小时
Just a couple of hours ago,
但现在他死了  我
and now he's dead. I...
你知不知道他为什么去那里
Do you know of any reason why he'd be in that part of town?
不知道
No.
他的办公室在市中心
His office is, uh, in midtown.
离第九大街远得很
It's nowhere near ninth.
他什么时候离开家的
What time did he leave the apartment?
6点左右
Around 6:00.
他刚旅行回来
He had just gotten back from his trip
说要去处理些文件
And, uh, he said he needed to catch up on some paperwork.
他说只去几个小时
He said he'd only be gone for a couple of hours.
你是说旅行
You said a trip?
他在爱伯克奇参加培训研讨会
He was in Albuquerque on a training seminar.
只有两晚
It was just two nights.
你最近是否发现有什么不对劲吗
Did you notice anything unusual recently,
他有没有什么奇怪的行为
Any strange behavior?
他加班到很晚
Well, he, he had to work late
比平时更晚一些
A little more often than usual.
但在现在的经济情况下  谁不是呢
But I mean, in this economy, who doesn't?
去年他被迫裁掉部门的一半员工
He had to lay off half his department last year.
你确定他是加班
And you're sure he was working late?
你什么意思  说他有外遇吗
What are you saying, that he was cheating?
每晚  他走进那扇门
Every night, he would walk through that door,
孩子们都跑进他的怀抱  知道吗
And the kids would just race into his arms, okay?
现在他不在了
And now he's gone.
所以别问我  他是否真的是在加班
So don't ask me if he was really working late.
告诉我他为什么遇害
Tell me why he was killed.
他不是这个意思
He didn't mean to imply--
-有没有人深夜给他打电话  -卡塞尔
- What about phone calls, maybe late at night? - Castle.
有的
Yeah. Yeah. Um...
有个被约翰解雇的人
one of the guys that John fired--
马科斯·哈沃斯多克
Max Haverstock.
他有在深夜给我丈夫打电话
He would call hi late at night,
因为那些事  对他大吼大叫
And he would yell at him, all sorts of things.
我想他很痛苦  他需要钱
I guess he was hurting, he needed money.
我要约翰挂断他电话
And I, I told john that he should just hang up on him.
但约翰说不能
And john said no, he, he couldn't do that.
约翰给他钱了吗
Did he ever give him money?
我的丈夫不同意施舍
My husband didn't believe in handouts.
他认为人应该自力更生
He believed that a man should make his way.
我丈夫现在在哪里
Where is he?
我想跟他告别
I'd like to say good-bye.
关于这件事
About that. Um...
真尴尬
That was awkward.
这根本无法理解
it just, it doesn't make any sense.
死者家庭是稳定的中产家庭
The guy's got a stable, middle-class life--
好工作  幸福的家庭
Good job, good family.
也许他的朋友马科斯嫉妒他
Maybe his friend max was jealous.
是的 也许嫉妒到足以谋杀
Yeah, maybe enough to kill him,
但至于偷尸体吗
But to steal his body?
埃斯波西托
Hey, Esposito.
你帮我查查受害人的一个朋友
I need you to look up a friend of the vic.
马科斯·哈沃斯多克
Max Haverstock.
找到他  再带过来
Okay, find him and, uh, bring him in.
谢天谢地  你回来了  你还好吗
Dad. Thank god you're home. Are you okay?
我很好  怎么了
Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
很好  我们听说有蒙面持枪歹徒抢尸体
Fine? Masked gunmen, body snatchers?
我快给你发了一千条短信了
I texted you like a thousand times.
对不起  一定是关机了
Oh, I'm sorry. My phone must've been off.
你们怎么知道的
How--how did you know?
贝克特打电话了
Beckett called.
真的
Really?
她只是想让我们知道你们没事
She just wanted to let us know you were all right.
这么说她原谅你了
So has she forgiven you?
还没有  不过我在努力
Uh, not exactly, mother. But I'm working on it.
她同意我帮助处理这件案子
She has agreed to let me help on the case.
我想这是个不错的开始
Well, that's a start, I suppose.
不仅仅是开始  更是一次机会
It is more than a start. It is an opportunity.
她可能在我们之间竖起了一面高墙
She may have built a wall between us,
那我就要在这面墙上修一扇门
But I am going to...build a door in that wall,
要么就摆上一个梯子  要么挖个大洞
Or put up a ladder or dig a hole.
那你有法子了吗
You have a strategy?
惯用手法  用气质迷倒她
Be my usual, charming self.
有方案二吗
Uh-huh. What about plan "B"?
情况很糟吧  你当时害怕吗
So was it awful? Were you scared?
我  害怕
Me, scared?
不可能  得了吧
No way. Come on.
-抱歉我得去换个短裤  -爸爸
- Now excuse me while I change my shorts. - Dad.
好  我是很害怕  还好他们只要尸体
No, I was scared. But all they were after was the body.
-为什么  -我也想问为什么
- Why? - Why indeed.
老爸  你在哪里  老爸  你还好吗
"Dad, where are you? Dad, are you all right?
老爸  马上回电话
"Dad, call us right away.
老爸  周五我能和欧文
Dad, can I go see 'fame'
一起去看《名扬四海》吗
With Owen on Friday?"
你的关心很感人
Your concern is touching.
这条是我知道你没事之后发的
Okay, that one was after I knew you were all right.
我还以为我们一起去看的
Yeah, but I thought we were gonna go see that together.
还是可以的
We were, and we still can.
但是他邀请我下周五一起去看
But he invited me to go see it with me next Friday.
你宁愿跟男朋友一起  而抛弃自己的老爸
You'd rather go with your boyfriend than your dad?
你怎么搞的
What is wrong with you?
如果你真想跟我一起去  我就跟你去
If you really want me to go with you, I will.
不必了  你跟欧文说这次他赢了
No, no. You tell Owen he has won this round.
不过你要跟我一起看《圣诞欢歌》
but I got dibs on "A Christmas Carol."
谢谢老爸
Thanks, dad.
-真高兴你没被那些人杀死  -我也是
- And I'm glad you weren't killed by body snatchers. - Me, too.
好莱坞除了重拍这两部电影
Oh, they remade "Fame" and "A Christmas Carol."
就没有其他好点子了吗
Has Hollywood totally run out of ideas?
他们刚决定把游戏《星际大战》拍成电影
Well, they just optioned, uh,"Asteroids" the video game.
所以我同意你的看法
So my guess is yes.
但瑞安·雷诺兹正在拍一部三角爱情戏
But Ryan Reynolds is playing the wee triangle,
他演得还不错
And he's good.
你确定是这个人吗
Are you sure this is the guy?
马科斯威尔·哈沃斯多克
Maxwell Haverstock.
他承认认识被害人
And he confirmed he knew the vic.
这家伙从屋顶  丢块湿海绵都丢不动
This guy couldn't throw a wet sponge off the roof
更别说丢尸体了
Let alone a body.
-哈沃斯多克先生  -是我
- Mr. Haverstock. - Yes.
知道为什么请你来这吗
Do you know why you're here?
不知道  他们只说要我来
No. Uh, they just told me I needed to come in.
是关于约翰·艾伦的事  昨晚他被谋杀了
It's about John Allen. He was murdered last night.
太可怕了
Oh, that's terrible.
-你跟他是朋友吗  -我在他隔壁办公
- You and he were friends? - Uh, we had adjoining cubicles.
你最后一次看到他是什么时候
When was the last time you saw him?
自从行动日之后就没见过
Oh, uh, not since "D" day.
我们都这么叫
That's, uh, that's what we called it.
-行动代表裁员  -你被裁了吗
- You know, "d" for downsizing. - You were let go?
-是的  -我猜你肯定愤愤不平
- Yeah. - I bet that made you pretty angry.
是啊  我们一起工作了十五年
Yeah, 15 years, we worked there together.
人们都认为这有特殊意义
You know, you'd think that would mean something.
会觉得忠诚比其他一切都重要
You'd think that loyalty would be worth something.
你们懂吗  这是防备不及的重大挫折
You know what it's worth? A kick in the teeth!
你跟约翰打电话说过这些吗
Did you ever call and tell john that?
一直都这样  我跟他说过
Oh, yeah, all the time. Yeah, I told him
我们不该就这样被裁掉
We didn't deserve to be treated like that.
我跟他发誓  总有一天咸鱼会翻身的
But I promised him, one day, rhe worm would turn,
因为命运是个可恶的小贱人
'Cause karma's a nasty little bitch.
你杀他就是因为这个
Is that why you killed him?
-杀谁  -约翰
- Who? - John.
我为什么杀约翰
Why would I want to kill john?
因为炒了你
For firing you.
他没有炒我  我们在行动日一起被炒了
He didn't fire me. We were let go together on "d" day.
幸运的是我找到了另一份工作
Uh, fortunately, I was able to find another job.
他没有工作吗
He didn't have a job?
我想他没有再找
I guess he, uh, doesn't have to look for one anymore.
贝克特  调查结果出来了
Hey, you, Beckett. Story checks.
约翰·艾伦八个月前被解雇了
John Allen was laid off eight months ago
就在美国国际集团遭遇危机的时候
When the A.I.G. crisis hit.
爱伯克奇那边怎样
What about Albuquerque?
没有约翰·艾伦
No record of a John Allen
从附近三个州坐飞机的记录
Coming back from any flight in the tri-state area.
这让人怀疑他还对妻子隐瞒了什么
Well, it makes you wonder what else he lied to his wife about.
还有他是怎么继续生活的  我是贝克特
And how he paid all of his bills. Beckett.
好的  谢谢
All right. Uh, thank you.
再一次  发现尸体
They found his body...again.
什么情况
What happened?
有人解剖了他
Someone...operated on him.
解剖
Operated?
有人剖开他的腹部  拿走他的所有器官
They cut him open and took all of his organs out.
有人讨厌他的内脏
Somebody hated his guts.
动手的人不是外科医生
The guys who did this weren't surgeons.
切口不争气  用的是美工刀和厨房刀具
The cuts are sloppy, box cutters and kitchen knives.
能推测出他们在找什么吗
Any idea what they were looking for?
毒理测试显示血管里没有毒素
I ran a tox screen and found nothing in the bloodstream,
但体腔里验出
But in the body cavity itself,
微量粉状可卡因
There were trace amounts of powder cocaine.
他在帮着偷运毒品
He was their drug mule.
猜想毒贩等不及他用老办法运毒了
Guess they couldn't wait for him to pass the packets the old-fashioned way.
我不同意
I don't buy it.
一个人到中年
How does a middle-aged insurance actuary
无吸毒记录
With no history of substance abuse,
无犯罪记录的保险精算师怎么会偷运毒品
No criminal record, become a drug mule?
而且他也不像坏人
And this was not a bad guy.
这不是在克雷格列表网[分类广告网站]
You don't just fill out an ad
填张广告
On craigslist.
你需要了解人  尤其是坏人
You gotta--you gotta know people, bad people.
最古怪的是
As freaky as all this is,
不要忘了  解剖发生在死亡后
Let's not forget it happened postmortem.
直接死因在这里
The actual cause of death is up here.
淤痕说明凶手是用双手掐死他的
Bruise pattern indicates the assailant strangled him with both hands.
这里的瘀伤较轻
The bruising is a little lighter right there.
说明什么
What would account for that?
可能是手指脱臼或者断指
Dislocated or broken finger maybe.
也可能是他精心设计的
Maybe he's fancy.
掐死人的时候翘起小指
Strangled people with his pinkie sticking out.
就像喝茶一样
Like tea.
我刚从国土安全局回来
I just got off with homeland security.
出境记录显示约翰·艾伦
Passport records indicate that John Allen
是从墨西哥回国  不是新墨西哥州
Was coming back from Mexico, not new Mexico.
没有犯罪记录  身体健康的白人中产阶级
No criminal history, healthy, white, middle-class--
海关人员都不会看他第二眼
They wouldn't have looked at him twice at customs.
这家伙很有本事  怎么去做这种蠢事
The guy had skills. Why would he do something so stupid?
因为他必须这么做
Because he had to.
我刚刚和他妻子核实了经济情况
I just went over financials with the wife.
有多糟
How bad?
过去半年  他们一直靠信用卡过活
They've been living on credit cards the last six months.
他妻子被蒙在鼓里  还以为一切正常
She had no idea. She thought everything was fine.
如果他每天不工作的话
Well, if he wasn't going to work every day,
-他会去哪里  -找工作
- Where was he going? - He was applying for jobs.
我在他电脑里找到几百张求职信和简历
I found hundreds of cover letters and resume on his computer.
搞不懂  他们为什么不卖掉公寓
I don't understand. Why didn't they just sell the apartment?
-还收不回首付和按揭  -真是太惨了
- Wasn't worth the mortgage. - Man, that's harsh.
人寿保险呢
Life insurance?
四个月前就停止投保了
Mm. Stopped making payments four months ago.
这家伙已经没希望了  无论是生海是死
Guy was basically worthless, alive or dead.
是的  我是瑞恩
Yeah, Ryan here.
我理解他的绝望
You know, I get desperation,
也能理解他急需钱去运毒
I get needing the money, I even get being a drug mule.
我不懂的是  他怎么找到这份差事的
What I don't get is, where did he get the job?
好的  谢谢  比尔
Yeah, thanks, bill.
犯罪现场小组刚才来电话
That was C.S.U.
由于罪犯戴手套作案
Because our perps were wearing gloves,
车上发现的指纹属于车主
The only prints they could grab off the car belong to the owner,
而他昨晚报案自己的车被偷
Who reported it stolen last night.
看来我们没在这找到突破口
Looks like we're not gonna grab a break on this one.
在现场发现的那个手套呢
What about the glove we found at the scene?
也被清理过了  什么都没有
Dusted it, too. Nothing.
-里面也查过了吗  -里面
- Did you dust inside?  - Inside?
对  手套内层
Yeah, inside the glove.
要来点音乐吗
You want me to put on some music?
《犯罪现场调查》里他们干活的时候
Whenever they do this sort of thing on "CSI,"
总是会在昏暗的小屋里放点音乐
They always do it to music in poorly lit rooms.
有点让我想起黄片
Kinda reminds me of porn.
卡塞尔  闭嘴
Zip it, Castle.
没想过当个模特么
Ever consider becoming a model?
继续说话  就让你试试这个
Keep talking, and I'll practice on you.
抓到你了  王八蛋
Got you, you son of a bitch.
不错  记录在案
Boom. Got a hit.
路德·怀特黑德
Luther Whitehead.
两次因为蓄意持有毒品被捕
Bust twice for possession with intent.
一次因为合谋  这三个罪名都脱罪了
Once on conspiracy. Pled out on all three.
在州北部因为枪支交易被捕一次
Did a nickel upstate for a gun charge,
现正假释中
And is currently on parole for conspiracy to distribute.
看来他的假释要被取消了
Something tells me his parole's about to be revoked.
有地址没
You got an address?
趴在地上  趴下去
On the ground! Get on the ground!
举起手来  不准动
Hold it right there! Nobody move!
手放在后面  手放在后面  手
Hands behind your back! Hands behind your back! Hands!
律师先生  我肯定他们非法持有枪支
Counselor, I have them dead to rights on weapons
袭击警方  亵渎尸体
Possession, assault, desecration of a body
还有很多其他罪名
And about a dozen other things
我还没时间去想
I haven't even begun to think about yet.
我有什么理由同意呢
What is my incentive to cut a deal?
-他们没有参与谋杀  -给我点时间
- You don't have them on the murder.  - Give me time.
你没必要浪费时间  因为他们没做过
You don't need time because they didn't do it.
数罪并罚会判十年
Ten years concurrent on all charges,
只定五项罪名
Eligible in five,
这样他们会告诉你  他们知道的一切
And they'll tell you everything they know.
他当时是去见你
He was coming to see you.
在第九大街的一家破旅社
At a flophouse on ninth.
他本该七点左右到
He was supposed to be there by 7:00.
但胃里装着0.75毫升可卡因的家伙
But this guy, he got three-quarters of a mil worth
最终没出现
Of our coke in his stomach, and he don't show.
-你做了些什么  -我们去找他
- So what'd you do?  - We were gonna find him.
然后听到警笛声  很多警笛
That's when we heard the sirens. Lots of 'em.
我们下楼  沿着街区走
We go downstairs, walk up the block,
猜猜我们看到什么了
And guess what we see.
一群警察站在树下
A bunch of cops standing there behind a tree.
一棵很大的树  那家伙就在树上
A friggin' tree. The dude was in a tree.
-所以你们就等着  -唯一能拿回尸体的办法
- So you waited?  - The only way to get the body back.
我们没法以正常方式拿回货来
We couldn't get the packets via the usual method.
所以你们临时决定这么办
So you improvised?
没关系  他已经死了
Doesn't matter. He was already dead.
他为什么开始运毒
So why'd he start ling?
和所有人一样  绝望
Same as anyone. Desperation.
就像
It's just...
他看上去不像那种人
He doesn't seem the type.
只要逼得够狠  谁都会成为那种人
Anybody's the type you push 'em hard enough.
这家伙欠着债
I mean, the guy owed.
他像在体育真人秀里  只有防守的份儿
He was, uh, fourth and long with the clock running out.
-他遇见谁了  -没有说  但是他很害怕
- Who was he into?  - Didn't say, but he was scared.
你想知道谁是凶手  得先找到他欠谁的钱
You want to know who killed him, you find out who he owed.
不  不是  我需要更多的信息
No, no, no, no, no. I'm gonna need more.
-我要知道是谁做了担保人  -担保人
- I'm gonna need to know who vouched.  - Vouched?
-担保约翰·艾伦  -受害者  帮你们运毒的
- For John Allen...-our vic, your mule.
有人把他带来见你  一个你信赖的人
Somebody brought him to you, somebody you trusted.
还是说  随便一个无路可走  没有犯罪记录的
Or do you just do business with every desperate white boy
白人就能加入你们
With no history of criminal activity?
见鬼  老兄  你怎么知道他不是警察
Hell, man. How'd you know he wasn't a cop?
-得去打印了  -罗恩·毕格比
- Got the Printout.  - Ron Bigby.
他是高盛交易所的场内交易商
He's a floor trader at Goldman.
受害者的妻子从没听过这个名字
Vic's wife never heard the name.
一个人靠评估风险赚生活
For a guy who assesses risk for a living,
那他肯定冒着极大的风险
He sure does seem to take a lot of 'em.
看看在哪里可以找到他
Yeah, well, look where it got him.
-抓住他  -明白
- Pick him up.  - You got it.
卡塞尔
Castle.
-死了  -是的
- Dead?  - Yeah.
-等下  死了吗  -毕格比先生  随你问多少次
- Wait. Dead?  - Mr. Bigby, you can ask as often as you like.
答案都不会变的
The answer is not gonna change.
这真是遗憾  真的真的很遗憾
Oh. That is a damn shame. That is a damn, damn shame.
我是说  你知道约翰·艾伦是谁吗
I mean, do you know who John Allen is? Huh?
他就是现代版的威利·洛曼[伟大的推销员]
He's the new Willy Loman. Okay?
每个人都是人情淡薄的受害者
Every man victim of an apathetic world.
天  我觉得应该找人写个剧本
God, I swear. Someone should write a play.
-你写剧本吗  -不写
- Hey, do you write plays?  - Unproduced.
毕格比先生  该我们提问了
Mr. Bigby, it's come to our attention
你最近帮艾伦先生找了份工作
That you recently obtained employment for Mr. Allen
运毒
As a drug mule.
-你知道这事了  -是的
- You know about that? - Yeah.
罗恩  坏消息
And bad news, Ron.
你得去找个新毒贩了
You're gonna have to find a new dealer.
-他们说了什么  -是你介绍艾伦去的
- What'd they tell you?  - That you got him an introduction
-还给他做担保  -好的  听着
- And that you vouched for Mr. Allen.  - Okay, look.
是他走投无路来找我
He--he came to me desperate, all right?
他记起我某晚在桌上跟他说的故事
He--he remembered a story I told one night at the table.
桌上
The table?
对  牌桌
Yeah, poker table.
我们在市里参与流动游戏
We're in one of the floating games around town.
小赌怡情  又排解压力
You know, small stakes, right? But good way to blow off steam.
但当他失业以后  就不再是个游戏了
But then when he got laid off, it stopped being a game.
他开始靠赌博来挣取他的生活费
He started betting to make up his paycheck,
但是赌注太小了
But the stakes were too low.
所以他去了唐人街
So he went to chinatown.
地下赌庄
The mob-run games.
对  三和会  他有时候做得不错
Yeah, triads. He did fine for a bit, you know?
但是  运气是个变幻无常狗东西
But...luck's a fickle bitch.
他输掉的次数比赢得次数多
He lost more than he had to the wrong guy.
他输掉的太多
He couldn't make enough to cover his losses.
对  那时他想起我跟他说的故事
Yeah, that's when he remembered the night I told the story
跟我个人的财务危机有关
About my own fiscal emergency,
关于我怎样去墨西哥
About how I went to Mexico,
怎样一天赚5万美元
Made 50 grand in one day.
那时候我才想到  有什么关系
That's when I figured, hey, what the hell?
-先付钱就是了  -他的债主
- Just pay it forward. - All right, this guy that he owed--
他有给你说过长相或是提到名字吗
Did he give you a description, name?
没有名字
No name.
约翰认为他是俄国黑手党
John thought he was Russian mafia
他的纹身布满全身
Because of all his tattoos.
如果一个俄国纹身暴徒紧追不舍
If some tatted-up Russian mobster was after me,
我可能会接受运毒这个工作
I could see taking a job as a drug mule.
一个在纽约市的俄国纹身男吗
A tattooed Russian in New York City?
-范围缩小了  -基于现有的信息
- Well, that narrows it down.  - We conduct an investigation
我们来进行调查
Based on the information we have,
不是我们需要的证据
Not the evidence we need.
毕格比说俄国男经常现身于
Well, Bigby says that the Russian hangs out
唐人街的俱乐部
At the club at Chinatown.
我们为什么不去那里呢
Why don't we just go there?
那些地方都是口口相传的  老兄
The games are word of mouth, bro.
-他们不会跟警察说的  -幸运的是  我不是警察
- They don't just share with cops.  - Well, luckily, I'm not a cop.
-卡塞尔  -怎么了  这很完美
- Castle.  - What? It's perfect.
我进去  四处观察  辨认出那个俄国男
I go in, scope the place out until I I.D. the Russian.
这不是个坏主意
Hey, you know, that's not a bad plan.
我们还是得找到赌博场所
We still have to find the game.
交给我吧
Leave that to me.
里奇  这故事很有意思
That's a pretty good story, Ricky.
是个好的开场  惊天大逆转
It's got a big opening, Major Twist.
我还是得说  我觉得运毒的人要出现了
Though I gotta say, I saw that whole drug mule thing coming.
康纳利  干得好  你难得没有挑刺
Nice try, Connelly. You're not gonna goad me into raising.
斯蒂芬  你以前写过一篇
Stephen, you once wrote about
-关于地下扑克的文章《金刚》  -所以呢
- An underground poker game in, uh, "King Con."  - Yeah?
你不是让哈里·博施
And you once had Harry Bosch
调查过那个扑克牌玩家被杀案吗
Investigate the murder of a poker player.
是  一美元赌注  怎么这么问
Yeah, "one dollar jackpot." why?
迈克尔  我们在找的那个家伙
Well, Michael, this guy that we're looking for,
他是唐人街三和会赌庄的常客
He's a regular in the triad-run games in Chinatown.
我想你们肯定认识能让我进去的人
I thought maybe one of you knew someone who could get me in.
你是疯了吗
What, are you nuts?
那里有很多流氓杀手
Those are crooks and killers down there.
里奇  做研究是一件事
Look, Ricky, doing the research is one thing,
但不用接近俄国黑手党  三合会吧
But the Russian mafia, the triad?
你和他们纠缠上的话
You tangle with those people,
就算是你的最畅销小说
And all the best sellers in the world
-也没法保护你  -不  我没打算卷进去
- Are not gonna protect you. - Oh, no. I don't plan on tangling.
我只是又一个无聊追求刺激的有钱人
I'm just gonna be another Rich, bored thrill seeker
想在那里试试运气
Looking to try my luck down there.
你一定很喜欢她
You must really like her.
谁
Who?
你那位女警官
That police detective of yours.
里奇  只有一个理由能解释
Look, Ricky, There's only one reason
你为什么会笨到要去那里
That you'd be dumb enough to go down there,
那就是你要打动那个女人
And that's to impress a girl.
你为什么放松一些
Now why don't you cut yourself a little slack
就买点花送给她吧
And just buy her some flowers?
你到底知不知道那个地方
Do you know the place or not?
拜托
Well?
你确信就是那里吗
Are you sure this is the place?
坎内尔从来没有指挥失误过
Cannell has never steered me wrong.
好了
Okay.
纽扣摄像机就位了  莱恩
Button cam's in place, Ryan.
图像清晰
Good for picture and...
声音也好了
Ah, sound.
好了  记住
All right, so remember,
我们能听见你那边的声音
We can hear you,
但你听不到我们说话
But you can't hear us.
所以一旦你出了这辆车  就靠你自己了
So once you leave this van, you're on your own, okay?
好的  把计划再说一遍
All right, tell me the plan again.
我进去  找到那个俄国纹身男
I go in, I find the tattooed Russian,
给他来个清楚的画面  然后出来
I get a clear picture of him, and I get the hell out of there.
如无必要  别待得太久
And you don't stay Any longer than you need to.
我会没事的  另外  这是唐人街
I'll be fine. Besides, it's Chinatown.
能有几个俄国人玩扑克
How many Russian poker players Can there be?
还有谁对此有不好的预感
Anybody else have A bad feeling about this?
我就是这么想的
That's what I thought.
开始
Go ahead and deal.
我进来了
I'm in.
俄国纹身男
Tattooed Russian.
又有一个俄国纹身男
Uh, there's another tattooed Russian.
有一桌子俄国纹身男
There's a whole table of tattooed Russians.
显然唐人街的俄国人
Apparently there are a lot more Russians
比我想象的多得多
In Chinatown than I thought.
俄国人是这里的常客
So...the Russians are regulars here,
但只有少数在无限制桌上赌博
But only a handful play at the no-limit table,
这正是约翰·艾伦会去的地方
Which is where John Allen would've gone.
那些人骗牌  加大赌注
The guy said they' card bullies, pushing up pots,
逼迫对手跟进
Forcing their opponents to bet more just to stay in the game.
你觉得他知不知道他说什么
You think he has any idea he's recapping a conversation
我们全都能听见
That we just heard in its entirety?
给他个小玩意  他就认为自己是詹士邦了
Give the guy a gadget, He thinks he's bond.
希望他在开溜玩两把之前
Let's just hope he remembers He's wearing a camera
-还记得自己戴了摄像头  -那你为什么
- Before he goes and takes a leak. - Why would you even--
-相信我  -走过去了  但我要玩把大的
- Trust me. - Coming rough, but I gotta stir it up.
我要去坐在桌子旁边
I'm gonna go sit at the table,
看看能不能查出什么线索
See if I can find anything out.
-他说什么  -他说他要找个座位
- What did he say? - He just said He's taking a seat--
那不是计划  那不是计划  卡塞尔
That's not the plan. That's not the plan, Castle!
怎么样
How's it going?
这是无限制桌
This is no-limit table.
很完美  因为我这人不喜欢有限制
Which is perfect, because I am a no-limit kinda guy.
请给我换二万美金
Change for $20,000, please.
不  不  他在做什么
No, no, no, no, no, no. What's he doing?
扔出我一半的年薪就像是扔零花钱
Dropping half my yearly salary like it was pocket change.
好身手
Nice tats.
身手  不  是说纹身不错
Ta--no, tattoos. The tat--it's nice.
他们说什么
What do they say?
说管好你自己的事
It says Mind your own business
-好好玩牌  -抱歉  我不是在瞎打听
- And play cards. - Sorry. Don't mean to pry.
我只是  我实际上只是个作家
I'm just, uh, I'm actually just a writer.
我只是做点小调查
I'm just doing a little bit of research.
作家吗
Writer, huh?
有没有我们可能听说过的什么作品
Anything, uh, we might have heard of?
《斯道姆来临》《斯道姆的最后一战》
Uh, "Storm Fall," "Storm's Last Stand."
-德里克·斯道姆  -是
- Derrick Storm. - Yeah.
我喜欢这家伙  你为什么把他写死
I love this guy. Why did you kill him?
说来话长
It's a long story,
但我现在在写另一部  地下玩家
But I'm working on a new one about, uh, underground poker.
很严肃的
Very hush-hush.
只是为了反映对社会的看法
Just kinda came down to get a feel for the world, you know?
你想让大家信任你吗
And you're--you want to try to be authentic?
没错
Exactly.
没问题
No problem.
是
Yeah.
看起来他在交朋友
Seems like he's making friends.
-他们说要赢光他的钱  -什么  你会说俄语
- They just said they're gonna take him for everything he's got. - What, you speak Russian?
大三大四间在基辅待了一段日子
Semester in Kiev Between junior and senior year.
有时候我郁闷了
Sometimes when I am bored,
就去小奥德萨的格雷奇科咖啡馆
I got to Glechik cafe in little Odessa
装作莫斯科人
And pretend to be muscovite.
真是很性感
Now that's kinda hot.
加筹码
Raise.
跟
Call.
我跟
I call.
注意玩家的手  看看是否有什么
Check the players' hands. See if there's anything
和死者脖子上的淤痕吻合
That'll explain the bruise Patterns on our vic's neck.
跟
Call.
卡塞尔先生
Say, Mr. Castle,
再多说说你的书吧
Tell me little bit more about this book.
是关于一个俄国歹徒的
Well, it's about a, uh, Russian mobster
他喜欢打牌
With a taste for cards.
他不顾一切掠人钱财
He, uh, preys Off of desperation,
引诱别人不顾财力加大赌注
Luring people in to bet him more than they have.
他为什么这么做
And why would he do this?
因为他还放高利贷
Because he's also A loan shark.
他找到受害者  拿到利息
See, he fronts his victims, and makes bank on...
他究竟在干什么
What the hell is he doing?
他在打牌  引诱其中一个人
He's playing poker. He's trying to provoke
放弃手里的牌
One of these guys Into giving up their hand.
-或是要套出凶手  -但有个人
- Or he's trying to tip off our killer. - But there's one guy,
一个有家的人  他陷得有点深了
A family guy, he gets in A little too deep,
无法还清债务
Can't pay the loan back.
所以那歹徒没有选择了
So the mobster...got no choice.
不得不杀了他
Has to kill him,
把消息传给债务人的雇主
Send a message to anyone else who owes him.
一晚  他把他引到一间废弃的大楼
So one night... He lures him into an abandoned building,
掐死他  然后把他从屋顶扔下去
Strangles him to death and throws him off the roof.
听起来写得很费力
Sounds like lot of work.
为什么不直接朝他头上打一枪
Why not just put bullet in his head?
容易多了
It's much more simple.
莱恩  仔细看看
Hey, Ryan, Check this out.
他用手指在干什么
What is he doing with his finger?
放大  那是个假体
Punch in on that. It's a prosthetic.
所以死者脖子上的伤痕会是那样
That's why it didn't leave A mark on our
那就是凶手
That's our guy.
如果他认为卡塞尔对他有威胁  他会
Hey, if he thinks Castle's a threat, he's--
我们得马上把他带走
We gotta get him outta there, now.
他们的保安武装得很好
Their security's pretty well armed.
我们以警察身份进去的话  会引起骚动的
We go in there as cops, it might get messy.
你要干什么
Oh, what are you doing?
我要进去
Uh, I'm gonna go in there,
如果十分钟后我还没出来
And if I'm not out in ten minutes,
你们就叫增援  请把我的包给我
You guys call for backup. Can I have my purse, please?
你打算干什么  用美人计吗
What are you gonna do, lip gloss 'em to death?
八九不离十
Something like that.
别这样嘛  伙什们
Oh, come on, boys.
我男朋友在里面玩牌  他还等着我
My boyfriend is waiting. He is player.
我不进去助阵  他会输钱的
If I don't go inside, he will lose.
我可是他的幸运女神
I'm his lucky charm, you know?
还不行
No?
兴许我也能带给你好运
Well, maybe I can be a lucky charm for you.
有我在  我们百战百胜
We win, and when I am in there, we always win,
走运的话  你或许也能分点甜头
And then maybe I can share some of my boyfriend's luck with you.
全押
All in.
作家先生  数目不小啊
It's a big pot, Mr. Writer man...
钱全在这里了
All that money.
不过这点钱对于百万富翁来说算得了什么
But then, what is money to millionaire, huh?
只要少缴点税就行
You just can write it off on your taxes
耍点小手段
Uh, as, uh, doing research.
全跟
All in.
你有点像自己小说里的人物
You are like character in your book...
陷得太深
In too deep.
三张Q
Three queens.
手气很冲
That's very impressive.
赢的机会很大
Not a lot can beat three queens.
可惜难敌五张顺子
Except an inside straight, maybe.
宝贝  专为你准备的
Sweetheart, this is for you.
能不能把这些换一换  以方便携带
Would you change this into something a little smaller that I can carry?
这数目可不小
Now that is a big pile of money.
不过这点钱对于强盗来说算得了什么
But what's money to a mobster, right?
别停下
Walk.
-你到底干什么的  -不是说了  我是作家
- Who are you? - I told you, I'm, I’m a novelist.
你听谁说的那个死人  房顶的故事
The story--the dead man, the roof, who told you?
-听谁说的  -他家人和孩子
- Who knows? - His family knows, His children know.
要是他还了钱  早可以回家老婆孩子团聚了
If he paid what he owed, He'd be home with them now.
可他却找死  现在你也想找死
But he crossed me. And now you have crossed me.
我不想死  我就是个写书的
No, no, no, I'm just a writer.
-别蒙我  你是警察  -他能是警察
- Do not lie. You're a cop. - Him, a cop?
别逗了  他当男人都不够格
Don't make me laugh. He's barely even a man.
贝克特
Beckett?
不过你算个纯爷们  长得也挺帅
But you are a man, aren't you? A very handsome man.
理查德  你怎么惹帅哥生气啦
Richard, are you bothering this handsome man?
滚开
Go away.
好吧  玩枪的小子
Okay, boys and their guns.
我以为自己还有点姿色
Am I supposed to be impressed?
这事与你无关
It doesn't concern you.
其实是
Actually...
有关系
It does.
这是我的幻觉  还是你真变了
Is it Just my imagination, or did you change?
卡塞尔  请叫支援好吗
Castle, could you get some backup, please?
-好的  -别出声  多谢合作
- Yeah. - Shah, shh, shh. Quiet. Thank you.
这边请
This way.
她怎么样
So how is she?
原本以为的一切竟然都是谎言
It's hard when everything you thought you knew
所以很难过
Turns out to be a lie.
并非全是谎言
Well, not everything was a lie.
起码她丈夫的爱是真的
Not her husband's love.
虽然有时候做错事  但出发点是好的
I mean, sometimes we do the wrong things for the right reasons.
结案了  你的《时尚》专访也能圆满结局了
So case is closed. I guess your "Cosmo" story gets a happy ending.
说到圆满结局
Speaking of happy endings...
还要谢谢你救我一命
Thanks for saving my life.
我不过是懒得写报告而已
I was just trying to avoid paperwork.
我们确实是最佳拍档
Ah. We make a pretty good team, you know?
就像《警界双雄》
Like Starsky and Hutch,
《坦戈与卡什》
Tango and Cash,
《福星和福将》
Turner and Hooch.
说起这部片子
You know, Now that you mention it,
你倒是很像福将  那只狗呢
You do remind me a little of hooch.
我猜你害怕了
It's because you're afraid, isn't it?
你不想让我追查你母亲的死因
You're afraid that if you look in to your mother's death,
你不愿再旧事重提  怕再次迷失自我
That you will go back down that rabbit hole and lose yourself again.
不过  今非昔比
But it's different this time.
我们有上乘的线索
We have good leads.
重要线索
We have strong leads.
这次你不用再孤军奋战
And you won't have to do it alone.
我来帮你
We can do it together.
要是我根本没想查呢
What if I don't want to know?
你有没有想过我是否想查
Did you ever think of that?
我没做好心理准备呢
What if I'm not ready?
要是抓到杀害我母亲的凶手
What if the idea of catching my mom's murderer
眼睁睁看着他却与警方达成交易
And then having to sit there and watch as he cuts some deal
坐十年牢后又自由了
That puts him back out on the street in ten years
让我很不爽怎么办
Makes me nauseous?
你挖我的老底不是为我好  而是为你自己
You dredged up my past for you, castle, not for me.
你太过自私  甚至都没注意到这点
And you're too selfish to even see it.
卡塞尔  这案子结了
The case is closed, Castle.
我们以前说好了  希望你能信守承诺
We made a deal, and I expect you to honor it.
创作呢
You're writing.
该写了
It's time.
贝克特呢
And Beckett?
很抱歉  爸爸
I'm sorry, dad.
电影看得好吗
So how was the movie?
没去
We didn't go.
-怎么没去  -欧文
- Why not? - Owen.
怎么了
What happened?
他游戏玩昏了头  错过了时间
He was playing video games and lost track of time.
他来得太晚
By the time he showed up, it was too late.
很抱歉  宝贝
sorry, sweetie.
他不光来晚了  还装出一副满不在乎的样子
And then when he did show up, He tried to act like It's no big deal,
弄得好像是我紧张过度
Like I'm overreacting.
甚至连通电话都没打
I mean, he didn't even call.
男生怎么都这样
Why do boys do that?
怎么能事事都狡辩
Why do they always have to justify everything?
说句对不起就这么难吗
Why can't they just say they're sorry?
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
你的坦诚布公
For just... being you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我错了
What I did was wrong.
辜负了你的信任  揭你的旧伤疤
I violated your trust, I opened old wounds,
违背你的意愿
And I did not respect your wishes.
也许我们以后没机会再见了
And if we're not gonna see each oath again,
我要对你说一声
Then you deserve to know...
非常抱歉
I'm very, very sorry.
卡塞尔
Castle.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
欢迎有能力的影视爱好者加入我们字幕组
加入仅凭个人兴趣爱好 没有任何金钱实质回报